<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>HeLsEroC</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2021-01-16T11:08:38+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>HeLsEroC</name>
   <email>marzoukiwissem.mw@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Abstract data type (ADT)</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/04/abstract-data-type/"/>
   <updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/04/abstract-data-type</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-it-is&quot;&gt;What it is?.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see what wikipedia says about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In computer science, an abstract data type (ADT) is a mathematical model for
data types. An abstract data type is defined by its behavior (semantics) from
the point of view of a user, of the data, specifically in terms of possible
values, possible operations on data of this type, and the behavior of these
operations. This mathematical model contrasts with data structures, which are
concrete representations of data, and are the point of view of an implementer,
not a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now from our prespective&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An abstract data type is a high level overview of a data structure which tells you
about the rules a data structure should adhere to but not about &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; they
are implemented which means we can have one ADT and many different
implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An abstract data type is an interface which does not give any details about the
internal implementation of a data structure, but &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; to use it, the user should
not care about the implementation unless they are doing a benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ADT is the &lt;strong&gt;blueprint&lt;/strong&gt; (which defines properties and operations) and the building is the concrete implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Data structure is the result of implementing an abstract data type .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract-data-types&quot;&gt;Abstract data types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Container&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Map&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graph&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;..etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need more informations, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_data_type&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
